Manish Dash Sharma

Software Developer

Bangalore (+91)7008974795 mdashsharma95@gmail.com

Experienced Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Skilled in Python, SQL Server, HTML, CSS, Django, App Scripting, Flask Rest-API. Strong engineering professional with an Undergraduate focused in Computer Science from MVJ College Of Engineering. Gifted and focused software developer who enjoys working in highly functional teams. Willing and enthused to resolve challenges in the most efficient manner.

EXPERIENCE

Dowell Research, Kerala — *Software intern*

SEPT 2019 to DEC 2019

 Development of Questionnaire Module – The questionnaire module developed using google sheet scripting, App Scripting. It fetches questions from the question database according to the selected groups by the owner and it generates google form using those sets of questions.

Dowell Research, Kerala—Software Developer

APR 2020 - Present

- Development of INSTALOADER UI (with python) using instaloader module – The python module instaloader which helps to download post, story, IGTV and many more from Instagram but it worked on cmd, to make more convenient to the user, I have developed a UI which is user friendly and serve all the work done by instaloader in cmd.
- Development of INSTALOADER UI (without python installed in the system) using the instaloader module – This is the second version of instaloader which works on the system which does not have python installed.
- Development of the INSTALOADER website using the instaloader module – Sending UI to someone can be a task, the website can serve the same and which can be sent to someone using a link.
 The website is developed using Django.
- Development of GitHub backup using flask web framework which helps to take backup of github repository and upload the files to mega drive.
- Developed a web app using flask, which uses a sign in /sign up module using face recognition. Technologies used are python, javascript, and ajax.

SKILLS

- C/C++
- Python
- Django
- Django-Rest Framework
- Flask Rest-API
- HTML/CSS
- App Scripting
- SQL Database
- MongoDB

HOBBIES

- National Level Basketball Player.
- Badminton
- Online Videos Game

LANGUAGES

- English
- Hindi
- Odia

GITHUB

https://github.com/manishda shsharma

- Developed a web based application using django which helps to digitalize the signing of the document for any organization.
 Technologies used are django, Javascripts, HTML & CSS, bootstrap.
- Currently developing a job-portal using django which has candidate login to apply for jobs and HR login to manage candidates. Technologies used are django, Javascripts, HTML & CSS, bootstrap.

EDUCATION

MVJ College of Engineering , Bangalore - B.Tech-Computer Science & Engineering

2014-2019

Vikash Institute, Bargarh

2014

PROJECTS

Major - IMPLEMENTATION OF SPEECH EMOTION RECOGNITION USING CNN AND RANDOM FOREST WITH TENSORFLOW

• The key to speech emotion recognition is extraction of speech emotion features. In this report, a new network model (CNN-RF) based on convolution neural network combined with random forest is proposed. Firstly, the convolution neural network is used as the feature extractor to extract the speech emotion feature from the normalized spectrogram used random forest classification algorithm to classify the speech emotion features. The result of the experiment shows that CNN-RF model is superior to the traditional CNN model. Finally, models can 'try to figure out' a human's psychology through speech emotion recognition and also know about people's happiness, anger, sadness and joy, achieving a more intelligent human computer interaction.

Minor - Amusement Park using OpenGL

• This project, "Amusement Park" aims at drawing a virtual amusement park. The park includes objects like the Giant Wheel, Columbus and the Roller Coaster. The Giant Wheel is visualized using circular rings. Rotation effects are provided for Giant Wheel. Swinging action is employed for Columbus ships. The Roller Coaster moves on a specified track. The tracks are created using Bezier curve functions with a set of defined control points. The whole scene is placed inside a texture mapped cube called SkyBox.